# Camille Gasser, PhD

ccgasser@gmail.com • github • google scholar

#### SUMMARY

PhD in Cognitive Neuroscience with 8+ years of experience in leveraging data to answer questions about human behavior. Expert in a range of quantitative research methods, with a flexible, curious, and self-motivated approach to experimentation and data analysis.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Science Intern**

August 2024 - present

Katch Data

 Conducted exploratory factor analysis (EFA) on a large-scale dataset to reduce 500+ movie attributes into 25 interpretable factors, enabling the creation of predictive models for generating movie recommendations

#### **Senior Research Scientist**

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2024

Columbia University

- ▶ Led 10+ in-depth projects on learning, memory, and decision-making, managing end-to-end workflows from experimental design to statistical analysis and reporting resulting in 8 peer-reviewed publications and 15+ presentations at international conferences
- ► Leveraged diverse statistical methods to analyze large-scale, highdimensional datasets (e.g., survey responses, fMRI data), keeping pace with evolving trends in behavioral science
- ► Crafted data-driven narratives and visualizations for cross-functional audiences (e.g., via slide decks, written reports, & dashboards)
- ► Established a novel summer training program to provide junior researchers with foundational skills in data analysis, statistics, and experimentation, with 50+ trainees admitted across 3 years
- ► Awarded honors and over \$100K in individual research funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH) & National Science Foundation (NSF)

## Research Manager

July 2017 - July 2019

New York University, Columbia University

- ▶ Integrated quantitative and qualitative methodologies across four collaborative research studies, ensuring robust research design, data collection, and statistical analysis for publication and reporting
- ► Managed end-to-end lab operations, including data management, grant preparation, and adherence with safety and regulatory standards

## **Undergraduate Research Scientist**

Sept. 2016 - May 2017

New York University

► Led an independent thesis project using predictive modeling to identify EEG signals indicative of future memory success

# Research Intern

Summer 2015 & 2016

Neuroscape, UC San Francisco

 Administered repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) to participants to investigate the neural basis of episodic memory

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Columbia University**

PhD in Cognitive Neuroscience, 2024 MA in Psychology, 2021 Advisor: Lila Davachi, PhD

# **New York University**

BA in Psychology (with honors), 2017 Minor in Math & Computer Science summa cum laude

#### **SKILLS**

## ▶ Data analysis & statistics

regression analysis
predictive modeling
Frequentist statistics
Bayesian statistics
data visualization
dimensionality reduction
natural language processing (NLP)

#### ▶ Research methods

experimental design
A/B testing
survey development
online experimentation
experience sampling
psychometric testing

## ▶ Languages & tools

Python

R

SQL

**MATLAB** 

command line (bash)

git

Markdown

Qualtrics

Microsoft Excel

- ▶ Data communication
- ▶ Project management
- ▶ Problem-solving
- ▶ Technical writing
- ▶ Teaching & mentorship